kwintessential.co.uk 2017-06-26

# Privacy Policy: Cookies and Personal Information - Kwintessential UK

## Use of Personal Information

This privacy policy sets out how Kwintessential Ltd, Unit 1 Crewkerne Business Park, Somerset, TA18 7HJ, UK uses and protects any information that you give when you use this website.

Kwintessential is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 1st July 2012.

### What information do we collect?

We may collect the following information:  
•    name and job title  
•    contact information including email address  
•    demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests  
•    other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

### Log Files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include  your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

### What do we do with the information we gather?

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

•    Internal record keeping.  
•    We may use the information to improve our products and services.  
•    We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.  
•    From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### How do we use cookies?

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

### Links to other Websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

•    whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes  
•    if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to us with full details.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

### Third Party Advertisers

Our site works with third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

We recognise that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit kwintessential.co.uk, and how we safeguard your information.  We never sell your personal information to third parties.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

As outlined above, we do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.  This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on Kwintessential.co.uk to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program, as well as the Kontera Advertising network) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

### Kontera and DoubleClick DART cookies

We also may use Kontera and/or DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick or Kontera advertising networks, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some advertisements).

These cookies are used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”).  The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey).  These cookies use “non personally identifiable information”.

They do NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security.  However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites.  This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program.  Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

  * You can review Google’s Privacy Policy by visiting <http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>

**Contact us**

For more information or to clarify any points with regards to our privacy policy, please call 01460 279 900.
